Israel, 1973... One woman stood between victory and defeat.
Golda is a drama, history, war film directed by Guy Nattiv.
Set during the tense 19 days of the Yom Kippur War in 1973, Israeli Prime Minister
Golda Meir is faced with the potential of Israel’s complete destruction.
She must navigate overwhelming odds, a skeptical cabinet and a complex relationship with US
Secretary of State Henry Kissinger, with millions of lives in the balance.
Her tough leadership and compassion would ultimately decide the fate of her
nation and leave her with a controversial legacy around the world.
Golda Meir, played by Helen Mirren.
Lou Kaddar, played by Camille Cottin.
Henry Kissinger, played by Liev Schreiber.
David 'Dado' Elazar, played by Lior Ashkenazi.
Moshe Dayan, played by Rami Heuberger.
Zvi Zamir, played by Rotem Keinan.
Golda is a 2023 biographical drama film directed by Guy
Nattiv and written by Nicholas Martin.
The film depicts the actions of Golda Meir, the 4th Prime
Minister of Israel, during the Yom Kippur War.
It stars Helen Mirren, Camille Cottin and Liev Schreiber.
It received its world premiere at the 2023 Berlin
International Film Festival on February 20, 2023.
It was released in the United States by Bleecker Street and Shivhans Pictures on August 25, 2023, and in the
United Kingdom and Ireland by Vertical Entertainment and MetFilm Distribution on October 6, 2023.
The film received a Best Makeup and Hairstyling
nomination at the 96th Academy Awards.
The film explores themes of israel, zionism, based on
true story, political leader, occupation.
The tone is emotional and thought_provoking and intense.